<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<root>
    <npc name="captain-carrion">
        <state name="default">
			<dlg if="UNLOCK_CARRION">Once more we meet, fellow traveler.</dlg>
            <dlg set="UNLOCK_CARRION" if="!UNLOCK_CARRION">Hello, fellow traveler.</dlg>
			<dlg>Captain Carrion is my name, and I come bearing greetings from the skies.</dlg>
			<dlg>However, I do not know the current whearabouts of my ship, the SS Sky Burial.</dlg>
			<option label="You are Captain Carrion?">
                <dlg>Ah, you have heard of me?</dlg>
                <dlg>I have always hoped my tales would reach others.</dlg>
				<dlg>Is it not the goal of all captains to be known one day as legends?</dlg>
				<option label="A legend?">
                	<dlg>Yes. A legend. I wish to be known among the skies.</dlg>
           		</option>
				<option label="I've never heard of you">
                	<dlg>:(</dlg>
           		</option>
            </option>
			<option label="The SS Sky Burial?">
                <dlg>A marvelous ship it is. Capable of flying the skies.</dlg>
				<option label="That sounds wonderful">
                	<dlg>Ah, it is. However, I cannot find it.</dlg>
					<option label="You lost your ship?">
						<dlg>I'm sure it will turn up eventually.</dlg>
						<dlg>A cup of coffee and a quick hike and I shall see to its recovery once again soon.</dlg>
					</option>
					<option label="Did you try calling its name?">
						<dlg>The ship is not alive, you know. Some even call it The Flying Carcass.</dlg>
					</option>
           		</option>
            </option>
        </state>
        <state name="same-costume" if="COSTUME_CAPTAIN_CARRION">
            <dlg>I am flattered to have inspired you to take upon my visage. Are you looking to be my protégé?</dlg>
			<option label="It's just a costume, bro">
				<dlg>Ah. Well. I fine costume, at least.</dlg>
			</option>
			<option label="Yes, but I cannot fly">
				<dlg>Good news for you, then, as I am the captain. Not you.</dlg>
			</option>
			<option label="Can we duel for the title?">
				<dlg>Unfortunately, this area does not seem to have combat mechanics. But I would win.</dlg>
			</option>
        </state>
		<state name="not-same-costume-but-pet" if="PET_CARRION_BIRD">
            <dlg>Ah, Davinky, following a new friend? Just be back before we set off.</dlg>
        </state>
    </npc>
	<npc name="box">
        <state name="default">
			<dlg>Hey, buddy, what ya lookin at?</dlg>
			<dlg>You a big box looker, huh?</dlg>
			<dlg>Like your packages currogated for her pleasure or somethin'?</dlg>
			<option label="I love packaging">
				<dlg>Hey, yanno, that's not half bad.</dlg>
				<dlg>I know I come off a lil rigid but it's all about the show, yanno?</dlg>
				<dlg>I was actually just thinkin, yanno, I got a lott on my mind.</dlg>
				<dlg>You wanna hear this box out?</dlg>
				<option label="I'll hear you out">
					<dlg>Great, great, awesome. Ya won't regret it.</dlg>
					<dlg>Ya really won't. Yanno. I had a cousin. He got a lotta styrofoam.</dlg>
					<dlg>Now that ya would really regret. That stuff goes all pshsht pshat you know the sound?</dlg>
					<dlg>Man I hate that stuff. And it never decomposes, yanno? It never goes back to nature!</dlg>
					<dlg>I like to think I'll be goin back to nature or somethin', maybe a nice forest, mulch, the works.</dlg>
					<dlg>Yanno I've held a couple things in my time. I was just thinkin' so many things, yanno?</dlg>
					<dlg>Gifts. Goods. Long term storage. Ya name it. If it fits in six sides, then I'm the box for ya.</dlg>
					<dlg>Sturdy too. Yanno how long a box can last in a warehouse?</dlg>
					<dlg>Lotsa folks, they don't like waiting around, but a box? We love this stuff.</dlg>
					<dlg>So anyways, what I was thinkin', yanno, and I've been doin' a lot of it.</dlg>
					<dlg>You ever do thinkin'? It's a good way to pass the time.</dlg>
					<dlg>And yanno, a box, we got a lot of time to pass. Tons of it.</dlg>
					<dlg>Of course we can't hold time, that's some of that abstract stuff, can't be doin' that.</dlg>
					<dlg>Nah we boxes? We like the real stuff. Give me some hard goods. Maybe some smaller boxes.</dlg>
					<dlg>That's what I live for, yanno?</dlg>
					<dlg>But yanno I was thinkin', like I was sayin' I was thinkin' earlier, I was thinkin'</dlg>
					<dlg>Well, yanno, I was thinkin' maybe I put my packages in the wrong box, ya feel?</dlg>
					<dlg>I'd say eggs in the wrong basket but I aint' a basket. I'm a box.</dlg>
					<dlg>But I could've done a lot more, yanno?</dlg>
					<dlg>Coulda been a contenda', a real pound for pound champion.</dlg>
					<dlg>You catch what I'm sayin' here? I coulda been a... uh... a pugalist.</dlg>
					<dlg>What do ya call that?</dlg>
					<dlg>Oh, yea.</dlg>
					<dlg>I coulda been a boxer.</dlg>
					<dlg>Coulda seen it now - six sides of fury. A rumble in the warehouse.</dlg>
					<dlg>Ya think they fly out the big time boxes to Manilla?</dlg>
					<dlg>Yanno? Federal Express or somethin? I coulda been living good.</dlg>
					<dlg>I'd been in a plane before, but yanno, cargo hold, well, I'd be cargo hold there too but.</dlg>
					<dlg>It'd just be a bit different, yanoo? Change of scenery.</dlg>
					<dlg>Coulda ended in the UK or somethin', met the Queen, wait, do they still have that?</dlg>
					<dlg>Heard they got a whole day about boxes over there. Boxin' Day or somethin'</dlg>
					<dlg>Sounds like my kinda place. Royal Post too.</dlg>
					<dlg>Anyways like I was saying, that's my way of life.</dlg>
					<dlg>Oh wait, I wasn't sayin' that? Ya sure? Well ya, so my way of life.</dlg>
					<dlg>My way of life is simple - be a box, sit around, hold things. And yanno? Not had a sad day in my life.</dlg>
					<dlg>Cause' when you holdin' it together, cause you gotta.</dlg>
					<dlg>You can really appreciate how great it is you can show up every day and hold things.</dlg>
					<dlg>Maybe it's not for everyone, but it sure is for me.</dlg>
					<dlg>So at this point you probably thinkin' if I got a point.</dlg>
					<dlg>Nah. I aint' got a point. Well. I got eight points technically. I'm a box.</dlg>
					<dlg>Well, I guess my point is this - if you need somethin' held, I'm your box.</dlg>
					<dlg>That's all I got, seeya round'</dlg>
					<dlg>Well, not round, cause I'm a box. Seeya square. Or somethin. Cube.</dlg>
					<dlg set="A_LOT_OF_PATIENCE">See ya buddy, and thanks for bein' a pal and hearin' me out</dlg>
				</option>
				<option label="Don't have the time">
					<dlg>That's too bad, that's too bad, well, come back again.</dlg>
					<dlg>I'll be right here, sitting around.</dlg>
				</option>
			</option>
			<option label="Get lost, box">
				<dlg>Who you callin' a box, buddy?</dlg>
				<dlg>Yanno what? Go box yourself</dlg>
			</option>
        </state>
		<state name="same-char" if="PET_BOX_PET">
            <dlg>See, this guy gets it.</dlg>
		</state>
		<state name="talked-before" if="A_LOT_OF_PATIENCE_and_!PET_BOX_PET">
            <dlg>Hey how ya doin'</dlg>
		</state>
    </npc>
	<npc name="durooge">
        <state name="default">
			<dlg>*Oh, how unpleasent. It's Durooge.*</dlg>
			<dlg>*Look at their spindly little arms. And their spindly little legs.*</dlg>
			<option label="Inspect them further">
                <dlg>*And their spindly little nose. And their spindly little cane.*</dlg>
                <dlg>*Hold on. These are all quite long, actually.*</dlg>
            </option>
			<option label="What do they want?">
                <dlg>*Probably money.*</dlg>
				<dlg>*Do you have any money?*</dlg>
				<dlg>*Probably not, considering Tankmas' target demographic*</dlg>
            </option>
			<option label="You mean scrooge?">
                <dlg>*No.*</dlg>
            </option>
        </state>
    </npc>
	<npc name="peanutbudder-santa">
        <state name="default">
			<dlg>*Ah. What a wonderful surprise, it's Peantbudder Santa!*</dlg>
			<dlg>*It's never a Tankmas without them!*</dlg>
			<dlg>*What kind of treats do they have in store for us?*</dlg>
			<option label="Peantbudder?">
                <dlg set="PEANUT_BUDDERED">*They have loads of the stuff. More than one can ever imagine.*</dlg>
                <dlg>*What life isn't improved with a bit of that good stuff?*</dlg>
            </option>
			<option label="What do they want?">
                <dlg>*Probably peanutbudder.*</dlg>
				<dlg>*Well, actually they already have that.*</dlg>
				<dlg>*So maybe just a smile?*</dlg>
            </option>
			<option label="What about the previous Tankmases?">
                <dlg>*There wasn't any peanutbudder involved, so it doesn't count.*</dlg>
				<option label="That sounds harsh">
					<dlg>*Yea well we don't make the rules here. And this is just a voice in your head anyways.*</dlg>
				</option>
				<option label="That sounds fair">
					<dlg>*They aint' lenient rules but they the rules that keep us safe.*</dlg>
				</option>
            </option>
        </state>
    </npc>
	<npc name="pony-boy">
        <state name="default">
            <dlg set="PONYABLE_CONTENT">Oh, hey, what brings a cool robot like you down here?</dlg>
            <dlg>I'm Ponyboy, nice to meet you!</dlg>
            <dlg>Can I interest ya in a game? We got lots of games down here!</dlg>
            <option label="Games?">
                <dlg>Yea we got tons of games. Beeping kind. Booping kind.</dlg>
                <dlg>Maybe a couple other kinds.</dlg>
                <dlg>I don't have any paper for tic-tac-toe...</dlg>
                <dlg>Usually Geo and I play it</dlg>
                <dlg>Oh well! Come back around and let me know if you need anything else!</dlg>
            </option>
            <option label="Who's Sunny?">
                <dlg>Sunny? Hardly know them.</dlg>
                <dlg>But they seem awfully relevant to this whole arcade's theme.</dlg>
            </option>
            <option label="I'm not a robot">
                <dlg>You're not?</dlg>
				<dlg if="COSTUME_G_BOT">I mean you're literally a big gold robot.</dlg>
				<dlg if="COSTUME_P_BOT">Aren't you... P-Bot?</dlg>
                <dlg>That's... impossible</dlg>
                <dlg>Are you really human?</dlg>
                    <option label="Yup!">
                        <dlg>YOU ARE?!?!</dlg>
                        <dlg>Would you like me to make you anything?</dlg>
                        <option label="Sure">
                            <dlg>Heck yeah! I can make Lemon Poppyseed pancakes, Cherry Chocolate milkshakes...</dlg>
                            <dlg>But, uh, they didn't give me any ingredients down here so... maybe not</dlg>
                        </option>
                        <option label="Maybe not now">
                            <dlg>Ok, no worries!</dlg>
                            <dlg>I'm ready and excited to make something for you when you're ready!</dlg>
                        </option>
                    </option>
                    <option label="Nah, I was just pulling your leg">
                        <dlg>Oh...</dlg>
                        <dlg>Well...</dlg>
                        <dlg>Let me know if you need anything else!</dlg>
                    </option>
            </option>
        </state>
		<state name="same-char" if="COSTUME_PONY_BOY">
			<dlg>I'm flattered. I guess you really are a robot now.</dlg>
		</state>
    </npc>
	<npc name="project-154">
        <state name="default">
            <dlg set="UNLOCK_PROJECT_154">*You found the thing thing!*</dlg>
            <dlg>*They seem very confused about being here*</dlg>
			<option label="I really love your role in Madness Combat">
				<dlg>*They seem rather insulted*</dlg>
            </option>
			<option label="So what's the new thing?">
				<dlg>*It's always a new thing with thing thing*</dlg>
            </option>
			<option label="When's Thing Thing Arena 5?">
				<dlg>*It seems like this thing's thing thing days are long past it*</dlg>
            </option>
		</state>
		<state name="grunt" if="COSTUME_MADNESS_GRUNT">
            <dlg>*Come on man you're really gonna dress like that in front of a thing thing?*</dlg>
		</state>
		<state name="hank" if="COSTUME_HANK">
            <dlg>*They could totally beat you in a fight, Hank*</dlg>
		</state>
		<state name="jeb" if="COSTUME_JEB">
            <dlg>*Don't be going after somebody for being called thing thing when your name is Jeb, Jeb.*</dlg>
		</state>
		<state name="auditor" if="COSTUME_AUDITOR">
            <dlg>*They don't seem particularly phased by your ominous powers, Auditor*</dlg>
		</state>
    </npc>
</root>