<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<root>
    <npc name="thomas">
        <state name="default">
            <dlg>Hello fellow newgrounder I am the tom fulp of the new grounds dot com</dlg>
            <dlg>Are we talking about tom fulp? I love talking about tom fulp.</dlg>
            <dlg if="SECRET_LOVE_OF_THE_TOM">btw I only say this to people I enjoy the company of. But I love you.</dlg>
        </state>
        <state name="default" if="THE_IRE_OF_TOM">
            <dlg>You disappoint me. Be gone from my sight.</dlg>
        </state>
    </npc>
    <npc name="tombstone">
        <state name="default">
            <dlg>Here lies Tankmas ADVENTure Calendar 2023's hopes and dreams.</dlg>
            <dlg>"I died before I could live."</dlg>
        </state>
    </npc>
    <npc name="concierge-invisible">
        <state name="default">
            <dlg>Yes. This is the concierge. Are you in need of something?</dlg>
            <dlg>I am busy. You can make me busier.</dlg>
            <dlg>As it is. Please move to the side for someone else to make me busy.</dlg>
        </state>
    </npc>
    <npc name="concierge">
        <state name="default">
            <dlg>Hello... Hello... Dear guests...</dlg>
            <dlg>Welcome... Welcome... It is now time...</dlg>
            <dlg>Le Portél de Geist does welcome you... Yes...</dlg>
            <dlg>If... Anything is of need... You can trust the concierge...</dlg>
            <dlg>We shall... Be able to acquire it for you...</dlg>
        </state>
    </npc>
    <npc name="concierge-old-old">
        <state name="default">
            <dlg>Good tidings... Future guests.</dlg>
            <dlg>Your patience will be rewarded... Shortly...</dlg>
            <dlg>Hotel Check-ins will be commencing... Any moment now...</dlg>
            <dlg>Warmth awaits you soon... Yes... Soon...</dlg>
        </state>
    </npc>
    <npc name="concierge-old">
        <state name="default">
            <dlg>Good tidings... Future guests...</dlg>
            <dlg>Do you desire... Accommodations of a warmer... Variety?</dlg>
            <dlg>All this... Could be arranged... If one is to be... Patient...</dlg>
            <dlg>For now... Consume golden morsels to your delight... For now...</dlg>
            <dlg>...For now...</dlg>
        </state>
    </npc>
    <npc name="lil-jimby">
        <state name="default">
            <dlg>Hey man whazz goin on</dlg>
            <dlg>I was telling you man big things coming soon, right?</dlg>
            <dlg>But I'm still thinking, like, there's even MORE coming</dlg>
            <dlg>I can feel it in my BONES man... and I don't even HAVE those man</dlg>
            <dlg>Stay tuned right here man big things comin soon</dlg>
            <dlg>You heard it from me first man Lil Jimby @ GeistBeatz dot com</dlg>
        </state>
    </npc>
    <npc name="lil-jimby-old">
        <state name="default">
            <dlg>Hey man whazz goin on</dlg>
            <dlg>Hey man I can feel it man big things comin soon man</dlg>
            <dlg>I can feel it in my BONES man... and I don't even HAVE those man</dlg>
            <dlg>Stay tuned right here man big things comin soon</dlg>
            <dlg>You heard it from me first man Lil Jimby @ GeistBeatz dot com</dlg>
        </state>
    </npc>
    <npc name="javert">
        <state name="default">
            <dlg>I see ze ringarde one has found their way in.</dlg>
            <dlg>Had your fill of your puff peasent treats?</dlg>
            <dlg>Or are you only here to get a whiff of ze superior culture? Hon hon hon!</dlg>
        </state>
    </npc>
    <npc name="javert-old">
        <state name="default">
            <dlg>C'est how you say the staging of ze big reveal</dlg>
            <dlg>O? You do not know what it iz I am talking about?</dlg>
            <dlg>So ringarde! Ze living do not appreciate ze vibez of de metaphyizical world, yes?</dlg>
            <dlg>Go on now to your little sweet puff peasent treats, hon hon hon!</dlg>
        </state>
    </npc>
    <npc name="mallow">
        <state name="default">
            <dlg>Shh... Dude... Keep it down!</dlg>
            <dlg>Did you see what's going on out there? They're absolutely crazy.</dlg>
            <dlg>They're doing the same thing every single day! Thousands of times!</dlg>
            <dlg>Impaling cute lil marshmallows just like me on wooden stakes! Then eating them!</dlg>
            <dlg>It's sick! But you wouldn't do that, would you?</dlg>
        </state>
    </npc>
    <npc name="backpacker-jill">
        <animation type="idle" sprite_anim="float-fast" />
        <state name="default">
            <dlg>Oh, hallo!</dlg>
            <dlg>Did you happen upon this hotel too? Very fascinating, yes?</dlg>
            <dlg>I was just hiking along, but then I saw it appear in the distance!</dlg>
            <dlg>I feel myself drawn to it, so much excitement, as are you, yes?</dlg>
            <dlg>Wunderbar! We will make this a home together, yes?</dlg>
        </state>
    </npc>
    <npc name="pompous-joan">
        <animation type="idle" sprite_anim="float-normal" />
        <state name="default">
            <dlg>Hmm? Sorry, were you trying to talk to me?</dlg>
            <dlg>You must have me confused for a commoner.</dlg>
            <dlg>Allow me to correct you, let's call it a charity, to the lesser beings like yourself.</dlg>
            <dlg>I am Joan. And YOU are not worth my efforts. Now begone.</dlg>
            <dlg>This premiere is far too exclusive for one such as yourself.</dlg>
            <dlg>Well... There's the door. So see yourself out the way you came.</dlg>
        </state>
    </npc>
    <npc name="mall-santa">
        <state name="default">
            <dlg>Grrch-gak...guh-</dlg>
            <dlg>AGH! YOU! PLEASE!</dlg>
            <dlg>This bag is much too heavy for my brittle 23 year old body! Would you offer this
                humble Mall Santa a hand?</dlg>
            <dlg>Here, just bend down and extend your arms like-</dlg>
            <dlg>...</dlg>
            <dlg>Where are you going?</dlg>
        </state>
    </npc>
    <npc name="gold-miser-jacquez">
        <animation type="idle" sprite_anim="float-slow" />
        <state name="default">
            <dlg>Hmmph? Do I owe you my time?</dlg>
            <dlg>No? I did not think so. But so many here owe ME.</dlg>
            <dlg>It's not easy being so generous, you know. I collect and collect. But then they ask ME for my worth.</dlg>
            <dlg>And, ME, being such a generous being, give them with the small ask they pay me back slightly more later.</dlg>
            <dlg>Of course... If they're late, well, then special arrangements will have to be made.</dlg>
            <dlg>And this hotel is *quite* late.</dlg>
        </state>
    </npc>
    <npc name="the-shape">
        <state name="default">
            <dlg>...</dlg>
        </state>
    </npc>
    <npc name="dr-good">
        <state name="default">
            <dlg>Haha! Thank you so very much for coming to see my movie!</dlg>
        </state>
    </npc>
</root>